<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Aspire Lite</string>

    <!-- Button strings -->
    <string name="PlantStageLabel">Plant stage:</string>
    <string name="BrixReadingsLabel">Brix% readings:</string>
    <string name="Plus">+</string>
    <string name="Minus">-</string>
    <string name="Reset">Reset</string>
    <string name="ResetAll">Reset all the entered Brix% readings?</string>

    <!-- Action strings -->
    <string name="Help">Help</string>
    <string name="Feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="Legal">Legal</string>
    <string name="About">About</string>

    <!-- Plant stage strings -->
    <string-array name="plant_stage_array">
        <item>Pre-harvest</item>
        <item>Harvest period</item>
        <item>Fern establishing</item>
        <item>Mid summer fern growth</item>
        <item>Late summer fern growth</item>
        <item>Dormancy</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Error/warning message strings for the Brix% readings analysis -->
    <string name="BrixErrorNotANumber">"Invalid number '%1$s'!"</string>
    <string name="BrixErrorOutOfRange">"Invalid Brix%% reading (%1$.0f is not between %2$d and %3$d!)"</string>
    <string name="BrixErrorTooVariable">"Outlier detected (%1$s)"</string>
    <string name="BrixErrorInsufficientValues">"Insufficient Brix%% readings entered (%1$d/%2$d)!"</string>
    <string name="BrixErrorOutOfRangeCHO">"Out of bounds CHO reading!"</string>
    <string name="BrixErrorUnknownStage">"Unknown plant stage '%1$s'!"</string>
    <string name="BrixErrorUnknownCategory">"Unknown age category '%1$s'!"</string>
    <string name="BrixCHO">"Estimated CHO: %1$.0f"</string>

    <!-- Help or documentation strings -->
    <!-- TODO: Implement most of these... -->
    <string name="HelpBlurb">
        Topics:\n
        &#8226; Plant stage definitions\n
        &#8226; Taking Brix% readings\n
        &#8226; App and model limitations\n
    </string>
    <string name="PlantStage">Plant stage</string>
    <string name="HelpPlantStageBlurb">
        The plant stage is used to correlate the CHO reading to the crop state.\n\n

        <b>Pre-harvest:</b>\n
        During late winter, before spear growth starts.\n

        <b>Harvest period:</b>\n
        Any time during spear harvest.\n

        <b>Fern establishing:</b>\n
        During the period after the end of harvest when the fern canopy is establishing.\n

        <b>Mid summer fern growth:</b>\n
        During the period of maximum fern activity, after it is fully established.\n

        <b>Late summer fern growth:</b>\n
        During the period when fern activity is starting to decline.\n

        <b>Dormancy:</b>\n
        At the end of fall, when ferns have died.
    </string>
    <string name="BrixReadings">Brix% readings</string>
    <string name="HelpBrixReadingsBlurb">
        Unfortunately, there is no documentation online describing how to collect the Brix%
        samples.\n\n
        As collecting the samples is both involved and vital to the accuracy of the result,
        you should only use this system if you have had prior experience an Aspire system.
        Hopefully this situation will change in the near future.
    </string>
    <string name="Limitations">Limitations</string>
    <string name="HelpLimitationsBlurb">
        Due to limitations of the underlying model, the generated information will not be valid
        for:\n
        &#8226; Crops in tropical regions\n
        &#8226; Young crops\n
        The app itself also does not make use of the region-specific models.\n\n
        See
        <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Sarah_Sinton/publication/253703294_Carbohydrates_and_Yield_Physiology_of_Asparagus_-_A_Global_Overview/links/5406201d0cf2bba34c1e3ed6.pdf">
            the original paper
        </a> for more information.
    </string>
    <string name="FeedbackBlurb">
        If you want to submit some kind of feedback, feel free to
        <a href="https://github.com/PlantandFoodResearch/aspire-lite/issues/new">raise an issue</a>
        on <a href="https://github.com/PlantandFoodResearch/aspire-lite">Github</a>.
    </string>
    <string name="LegalBlurb">
        <!-- TODO: This needs to be fixed before a release... -->
        There is no legal blurb! Oh no!
    </string>
    <!-- TODO: Get this checked, fix any mistakes, add attribution for the other people who also
        helped, etc...
        This is also not a legally binding disclaimer.
    -->
    <!-- Because we are formatting and using HTML tags, ensure that any tag starts are properly
        escaped. This does look quite ugly, but it works... and seems to be the recommended
        solution.
    -->
    <string name="AboutBlurb">
        &lt;i>%1$s %2$s&lt;/i>
        &lt;br />&lt;br />

        See
        &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Sarah_Sinton/publication/253703294_Carbohydrates_and_Yield_Physiology_of_Asparagus_-_A_Global_Overview/links/5406201d0cf2bba34c1e3ed6.pdf">
            the original paper
        &lt;/a> for details on the science behind the app.
        The comments for each situation were originally provided by Sarah Sinton.
        Some of the algorithms used are based off the code from the old AspireNZ DSS, which is now
        offline.
        &lt;br />&lt;br />

        The app itself is open source, and is hosted on
        <a href="https://github.com/PlantandFoodResearch/aspire-lite">Github</a>.
        &lt;br />&lt;br />

        This app was written by Alastair Hughes; as such, any mistakes will be his.
    </string>

    <string name="comment_d1_0">
        "Root CHO content is very low for this stage of the annual growth cycle, probably due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous fern growth season.  This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop. These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  If a spear harvest is attempted, yield will probably be very low and subsequent fern growth will be poor.  No spear harvest will allow a long fern growth period and, therefore, plenty of opportunity for root recovery for the following season."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d1_150">
        "Root CHO content is low for this stage of the annual growth cycle, probably due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous fern growth season.  This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Spear yield will probably be low.  A short harvest would allow a longer fern growth period and, therefore, more opportunity for root recovery after close-up."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d1_250">
        "Root CHO content is below normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle, probably due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous fern growth season. This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop. These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Spear yield will probably be lower than normal."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d1_350">
        "Root CHO content is below normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle, probably due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous fern growth season. This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop. These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Spear yield will probably be lower than normal."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d1_450">
        "The root system is full of CHO, as it should be at this stage of the annual growth cycle.  This is due to full replenishment of root CHO reserves during the previous fern growth season.  As a result, CHO availability will not restrict spear yield, and subsequent fern growth should be good."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_cu_0">
        "Root CHO content is very low for this stage of the annual growth cycle. This could be because the harvest was too long, but it is more likely a consequence of inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous fern growth season. The latter could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Low CHO availability will restrict initial growth of the ferns after close-up."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_cu_150">
        "Root CHO content is lower than normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle.  This could be because the harvest was too long, but it is more likely a consequence of inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous season.  The latter could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Low CHO availability may restrict initial growth of the ferns after close-up."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_cu_250">
        "Root CHO content is about normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle.  Root reserves must have been replenished fully during the previous fern growth season, and have not been depleted too much during harvest.  At the higher end of the range, spear harvest could be continued without harming the crop.  CHO availability is unlikely to restrict fern establishment after close-up."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_cu_350">
        "Root CHO content is above normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle.  Root reserves must have been replenished fully during the previous fern growth season, and have not been depleted during harvest.  Spear harvest could be continued without harming the crop.  CHO availability will not restrict fern establishment after close-up."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_fe_0">
        "Root CHO content is lower than normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle. This is likely to be associated with either excessive or poor fern establishment.  Excessive initial fern growth, which could result from too much water or fertiliser application, would cause a large CHO depletion.  Poor establishment would result from a root CHO content that was already low at close-up.  This could be because the harvest was too long, but it is more likely a consequence of inadequate replenishment of root reserves during the previous season."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_fe_200">
        "Root CHO content is about normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle.  Root reserves must have been replenished fully during the previous fern growth season, and have not been depleted too much during harvest or initial fern growth."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_fe_300">
        "Root CHO content is higher than normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle.  This condition is unusual because fern establishment is a heavy drain on root reserves, and much of the available CHO left after spear harvest is usually utilised during this phase. The high level suggests that spear harvest was too short, and could have been extended without harming the crop.  Alternatively, it could result from poor fern growth during establishment."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_fe_400">
        "Root CHO content is much higher than normal for this stage of the annual growth cycle. This condition is very unusual because fern establishment is a heavy drain on root reserves, and much of the available CHO left after spear harvest is usually utilised during this phase.  The high level suggests that spear harvest was too short, and could have been extended substantially without harming the crop.  Alternatively, it could result from poor fern growth during establishment."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg1_0">
        "Root CHO content is lower than normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle.  It should be recharging rapidly due to the activity of the established fern. The low value could result from poor fern establishment, fern still in the establishment phase, a recent new flush of fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  The latter could be caused by a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg1_300">
        "Root CHO content is not yet fully recharged.  It is about normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle, and should be increasing rapidly due to the activity of the established fern."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg1_400">
        "Root CHO content is higher than normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle.  It is almost fully recharged, but should still be increasing due to the activity of the established fern."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg1_500">
        "Root CHO content is fully recharged. This has occurred earlier than usual, perhaps because the CHO content was not fully depleted earlier in the season."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg2_0">
        "Root CHO content is much lower than normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle.  The CHO content should be almost fully recharged by this stage.  The low value could result from poor fern establishment, a recent new flush of fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  The latter could be caused by a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg2_300">
        "Root CHO content is lower than normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle.  The CHO content should be almost fully recharged by this stage. The low value could result from poor fern establishment, a recent new flush of fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  The latter could be caused by a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg2_400">
        "Root CHO content is about normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle.  It is almost fully recharged, but should still be increasing due to the activity of the established fern."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_pfg2_500">
        "Root CHO content is fully recharged. This has occurred slightly earlier than usual, perhaps because the CHO content was not fully depleted earlier in the season, but ensures that the crop is well set up for good performance next season."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d2_0">
        "Root CHO content is very low for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during fern growth.  This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Next season, spear yield will probably be very low if the crop is harvested and subsequent fern growth will be poor."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d2_150">
        "Root CHO content is low for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during fern growth.  This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Next season, spear yield will probably be low if the crop is harvested and subsequent fern growth will be poor."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d2_250">
        "Root CHO content is below normal for this stage of the crops annual growth cycle due to inadequate replenishment of root reserves during fern growth.  This could have resulted from poor fern establishment, additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Next season, spear yield will probably be lower than normal if the crop is harvested and subsequent fern growth will be poor."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d2_350">
        "The root system CHO content is good but not as high as it could be at this stage of the crops annual growth cycle due to incomplete replenishment of root reserves during fern growth.  This could have resulted from additional flushes during fern growth or premature fern loss or needle drop.  These may have been caused by too much water, a foliar disease such as Stemphylium or physical damage such as that caused by wind or hail.  Next season, spear yield could be reduced below optimum, especially if weather conditions are unfavourable for spear growth during harvest."
    </string>
    <string name="comment_d2_450">
        "The root system is full of CHO, as it should be at this stage of the crops annual growth cycle.  The high CHO content is the result of good fern growth and replenishment of root CHO reserves during the season. This ensures that the crop is well set up for good performance next season. CHO availability will not restrict spear yield and subsequent fern growth."
    </string>
</resources>
